{
  "topic_id":"103",
  "questions": [
    {
      "id": 1,
      "question": "Select the sentence in the active voice.",
      "choice": [
        " I like pies.",
        "The pies were eaten.",
        "The pies are being eaten.",
        "the ball is kicked"
      ],
      "answer": 0,
      "explanation": "the subjuct did the verb in choice A",
      "keywords": [{ "pies": "ኬኮች" }]
    },
    {
      "id": 2,
      "question": "Select the sentence in the passive voice.",
      "choice": [
        " The postman bite the dog.",
        "The dog bite the postman.",
        "The postman was bitten by the dog.",
        "All'"
      ],
      "answer": 2,
      "explanation": "subject is having the verb done in choice C",
      "keywords": [{ "bite": "ንክሻ" }, { "postman": "ፖስታ ቤት" }]
    },
    {
      "id": 3,
      "question": "Select the verb in the active voice \nMy music was considered uncool, but I always felt a connection with the audience. (Singer David Cassidy)",
      "choice": ["always", "connection", "audience", "felt"],
      "answer": 3,
      "explanation": "",
      "keywords": [{ "felt": "ተሰማኝ" }, { "audience": "ታዳሚዎች" }]
    },
    {
      "id": 4,
      "question": "His command ________________",
      "choice": [
        "promptly obeyed",
        "was promptly obeyed",
        "has promptly obeyed",
        "will promptly obeyed"
      ],
      "answer": 1,
      "explanation": "We use the passive voice when we want to talk about an action, but are not interested in saying who/what does/did it.",
      "keywords": [
        { "command": "ትእዛዝ" },
        { "promptly": "በፍጥነት" },
        { "obeyed": "ታዘዘ" }
      ]
    },
    {
      "id": 5,
      "question": "That portrait ________________ by my grandmother.",
      "choice": ["painted", "has painted", "was painted", "paints"],
      "answer": 2,
      "explanation": "Passive voice is used when the subject is not the doer of the action.",
      "keywords": [
        { "portrait": "የቁም ስዕል" },
        { "grandmother": "ሴት አያት" },
        { "painted": "ተሳለ" }
      ]
    },
    {
      "id": 6,
      "question": "They ________________ to the party.",
      "choice": [
        "have invited",
        "are invited",
        "have been invited",
        "have been inviting"
      ],
      "answer": 2,
      "explanation": "We use the passive voice, when the subject is not the doer of the action.",
      "keywords": [{ "invited": "ተጋብዘዋል" }, { "party": "ፓርቲ" }]
    },
    {
      "id": 7,
      "question": "You ________________ when the time comes.",
      "choice": ["will be told", "told", "will told", "have told"],
      "answer": 0,
      "explanation": "",
      "keywords": [{ "told": "ነገረው" }]
    },
    {
      "id": 8,
      "question": "Everybody ________________ with me.",
      "choice": ["agrees", "is agrees", "agreed", "agreed"],
      "answer": 3,
      "explanation": "Active voice is used when the subject is the doer of the action.",
      "keywords": [{ "Everybody": "ሁሉም" }, { "agrees": "ይስማማል" }]
    },
    {
      "id": 9,
      "question": "The ocean ________________ dry.",
      "choice": [
        "cannot pump",
        "pumped",
        "cannot have pumped",
        "cannot be pumped"
      ],
      "answer": 3,
      "explanation": "The ocean does not perform any action here so a passive verb is required.",
      "keywords": [{ "ocean": "ውቅያኖስ" }, { "pump": "ፓምፕ" }, { "dry": "ደረቅ" }]
    },
    {
      "id": 10,
      "question": "I was very ________________ in the lesson.",
      "choice": ["interest", "interested", "interesting", "is interesting"],
      "answer": 1,
      "explanation": "",
      "keywords": [{ "interest": "ፍላጎት" }, { "lesson": "ትምህርት" }]
    }
  ]
}
